Guide to The Echo's Photo Morgue RG 5.15.1a
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Echo Records
1986-2001
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Western Connecticut State University.
RG 5.15.1a
1 Linear Feet 1 box, 44 folders
The photographs and photographic negatives in this collection come from The Echo's 'Photo Morgue'. Some of these photographs were used in issues of The Echo, others were unused. They are kept in the original negative sheets. Some negative sheets have hand-written notes describing the subject, date, and photographer of the photographs. Other negative sheets are blank.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged by date. Undated materials are grouped by subject.
Scope and Content Description
Collection consists primarily of photographic negatives and some photographic prints. Topics include sports, campus events, parking, and new student orientation.
Materials were originally in binders by school year, with more recent negatives towards the front. Box 1, folder 44 contains instructions to the photo editor on how to use the photo morgue.
The Echo has existed since 1955, but this collection only covers from 1986 to 2001.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Biographical / Historical
The Echo has been the student newspaper of Western Connecticut State University since 1955. It is generally published weekly during the school year. It was preceded by The Supplement.
According to a 2008 copy of The Echo's constitution (found in box 28 folder 13 of the SGA Recrods collection), The Echo functions
... as a source of information, and through letters and commentaries as a medium, for the students, faculty, and administration of the University. It shall provide publicity for campus events and information about on and off campus situations that are of interest to the student body.
According to this 2008 constitution, editors and writers were paid for their efforts.
At one point, The Echo had ~700 square feet of office space. They lost about 100 square feet to an elevator in 1987, then moved to a smaller office in 2019.
Provenance
In 2019 The Echo moved to a smaller office. This resulted in less storage space. Audrey Redpath arranged to transfer the photo morgue of The Echo to the University Archives.
Related Materials
This collection does not include copies of The Echo. Copies of The Echo can be found in the Student Newspaper Collection at http://archives.library.wcsu.edu/findingaids/studentNewspapers.xml.
Some records regarding The Echo can be found in the collections Division of Student Affairs Records, Western Connecticut State University Photographs and Miscellanea, and Student Government Association Records.
Universities and colleges -- United States -- Newspapers -- History.; Universities and colleges -- Western Connecticut State University.; Photographs; Sonski, Jay; Staley, Heather; Bender, Dave; Tanner, Adam; Sweeney, Jen; Brodeur, Todd; Melvin, Annie; Dziatko, Gary
- Photographs
  - Photo Negatives, Identified, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General
    Contents: 26 negative storage pages, 3 envelopes. Topics: press pics; book store; Feldman; Midsummer Night; Faculty Senate meeting; Kara Krebs; Chrystene Cook; Mike Stankiewics; Computer; o'conner; Basketball; cow pictures; Louise Bigs; Football vs. Wagner; Art Show; football; women's basketball; inquiring photographer; Tod (band?); Blizzard of' Bucks; men's soccer; football; safe sex thing; basketball; field hockey; artwork
  - Photos and Photo Negatives, Sports, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Contents: 24 negative storage pages, one 5x3.5 b/w print, one 3.2x2.2 b/w print, one 5x7 b/w print. Topics: Sports: football; basketball; tennis, cheerleading baseball, soccer,
  - Photo Negatives, People, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Contents: 22 negative storage pages and two 3.5x5 b/w prints. Topics: People
  - Photo Negatives, Music/Theater, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Contents: 4 negative storage pages. Topics: Music/Theater
  - Photo Negatives, Other, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Contents: 3 negative storage pages. Topics: Other
  - Photo Negatives, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Contents: 1 negative storage pages. Topics: football; Colonial Classic
  - Photo Negatives, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Contents: 3 negative storage pages. Topics: Ping pong & pool tournament; around campus; commencement; snow
  - Photo Negatives, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Contents: 9 negative storage pages. Topics: Tennis; homecoming; football; Second City; Inquiring Photographer; Mr. Sullivan; Registrar office; library; Regency; Football; around campus; spring flowers
  - Photo Negatives, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Contents: 2 negative storage pages. Topics: Rugby; library campaign
  - Photo Negatives, Fall 1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Contents: 22 negative storage pages. Topics: clubs carnival; bagpipes; football; Blues travelers; Westfest 95; o'neill center; hypnotist; casino night; street fair
  - Photo Negatives, October 1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Contents: 11 negative storage pages, 4 prints; Topics: men's soccer; Floods & Football; Chris Nolan (DSXCI) Mock trial; Newman halloween bash; Denise Hogan; "Chorus Line" Play. Photographer information: JS = Jay Sonski; HS = Heather Staley; DB = Dave Bender; AT = Adam Tanner; JSw = Jen Sweeney; DT =; TB = Todd Brodeur; RL =
  - Photo Negatives, November 1995 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Contents: 10 negative storage pages; Topics: art show; snack bar; Western game vs. SCSU; UFO speaker; chorus line; men's scrimmage vs Antigua National; men's basketball practice; observatory opening; women's basketball; jazz concert; goodall lecture; pool tournament. Photographer information: JS = Jay Sonski; HS = Heather Staley; DB = Dave Bender; AT = Adam Tanner; JSw = Jen Sweeney; DT = TB = Todd Brodeur; RL =
  - Photo Negatives, December 1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Contents: 7 negative storage pages; Topics: women's basketball; men's basketball; Neil Postman; jazz concert; Hine's swim class; winter graduation;. Photographer information: JS = Jay Sonski; HS = Heather Staley; DB = Dave Bender; AT = Adam Tanner; JSw = Jen Sweeney; DT =; TB = Todd Brodeur; RL =
  - Photo Negatives, January 1996 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Contents: 8 negative storage pages; Topics: Students move in; new security boxes; head shot of Rich Ercole; Parking garage and University Place; cops on bikes; women's basketball vs. umass @ Boston; men's basketball vs. umass @Boston;. Photographer information: HS = Heather Staley; DB = Dave Bender; AT = Adam Tanner; TB = Todd Brodeur; AM = Annie Melvin; GD = Gary Dziatko
  - Photo Negatives, February 1996 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Contents: 17 negative storage pages; Topics: Men's basketball vs Umass Dartmouth; Bascom; IQ Photo; smoking; photo box; Ives auditorium; Williams Gym; Library; construction; adjunct meeting; IQ Photo; women's basketball vs. plymouth; men's basketball vs Plymouth; Paul Hines; Country line dance; IQ Photos; men's basketball. Photographer information: HS = Heather Staley; DB = Dave Bender; AT = Adam Tanner; TB = Todd Brodeur; AM = Annie Melvin; GD = Gary Dziatko
  - Photo Negatives, March 1996 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Contents: 11 negative storage pages; Topics: faculty art show; men's basketball; senator; open forum; IQ; Lecture: one woman show; Jazz concert. Photographer information: HS = Heather Staley; DB = Dave Bender; AT = Adam Tanner; TB = Todd Brodeur; AM = Annie Melvin; GD = Gary Dziatko
  - Photo Negatives, April 1996 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Contents: 24 negative storage pages; Topics: painting show, Shannon Faulkner, Lee lecture; IQ Photo; kids in cafeteria;2nd open forum @ Litchfield Hall; Alpha Delta P-sponsored egg hunt; printmaking show; men's basketball; cabaret; Pace packs up; career fair; Dr. Bahat (Jerusalem); Israeli speaker; violinist; improv dance; baseball; Conatus Poetry; A&E You Laugh You Lose; art; One Act Plays; SGA Officers Profile; garage opens; Bob Mintzer jazz;. Photographer information: HS = Heather Staley; DB = Dave Bender; AT = Adam Tanner; TB = Todd Brodeur; AM = Annie Melvin; GD = Gary Dziatko
  - Photo Negatives, May 1996 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Contents: 8 negative storage pages; Topics: Speak Out; Jazz Concert @ Ives; SGA Polling; Jeans Day; Food Service Surveys; University Place; Illustrations; rat. Photographer information: HS = Heather Staley; DB = Dave Bender; AT = Adam Tanner; TB = Todd Brodeur; AM = Annie Melvin; GD = Gary Dziatko
  - Photo Negatives, September 1997 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Contents: 11 negative storage pages. Topics: WCSU Football; women's tennis; welcome back dance; clubs carnival; construction; west side dorm; memorial hall
  - Photo Negatives, October 1997 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Contents: 7 negative storage pages. Topics: men's soccer; Prof LV - Observatory; women's volleyball tourney; football; carnival; library; snack bar
  - Photo Negatives, September 1998 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Contents: 36 negative storage pages. Topics: Aluminum Hall Construction; Campus Ministry; Cross walks; police cars; men's soccer; parking; STTC; student center ATM; midtown crosswalk; football v. Jersey City; volleyball invitational; women's volleyball; meteorology department and BSA; men's soccer; women's soccer; IQ Photo; football; handicapped access; Plans - Swing Building; date rape seminar; SGA;football; steel frame swing building; orientation dance; campus buildings; WXCI; student orientation; Haas Renovation; Echo moving; tree cutting; moving day
  - Photo Negatives, October 1998 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Contents: 36 negative storage pages. Topics: Homecoming; football; street fair; WXCI Alumni 25th Anniversary; BSA - Poetry; Soccer; men's soccer; Tom Deluca, Hypnotist; Onyx; women's soccer; Representative Maloney; Volleyball; dream week; homecoming kings & queens; failed bonfire; pool tournament; Rebecca Adamson Lecture; UMOJA Talent Show; Toni Gray;art @ white hall; more tennis; women's tennis; football; board of trustees meet; quad construction; steam pipes
  - Photo Negatives, November 1998 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Contents: 21 negative storage pages. Topics: SGA Candidates; Joe Torre; academic advisement center; swing building; game room; Jazz concert; football; white hall computer lab; rugby; blanket drive; lights on white street; happy bus; Pinney Hall Construction; student art; celtic thing; Halloween Jazz Concert; football; mock trial; Sigma Chi; lower tuition rally; youth for justice
  - Photo Negatives, December 1998 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Contents: 5 negative storage pages. Topics: SGA Meeting; Hole Concert @ O'Neill; Student Protect Muska's removal; art show @ white hall; student one act plays
  - Photo Negatives, January 1999 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Contents: 3 negative storage pages. Topics: burn kit; electric pimps; can o christmas; SGT Scagnetti
  - Photo Negatives, February 1999 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Contents: 5 negative storage pages. Topics: Hockey; blood drive; basketball; winter carnival
  - Photo Negatives, March 1999 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Contents: 7 negative storage pages. Topics: SGA Election; Jazz; PAZ Magician; Spring sing; Hockey; Wings; Pizza thing; Big chair
  - Photo Negatives, April 1999 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Contents: 7 negative storage pages. Topics: Craft fair; Johnes Fest; New student thing; softball; student art; death
  - Photo Negatives, May 1999 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Contents: 5 negative storage pages. Topics: May day; fashion show
  - Photo Negatives, August 1999 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Contents: 5 negative storage pages. Topics: Clubs Carnival; New student orientation
  - Photo Negatives, September 1999 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Contents: 2 negative storage pages. Topics: Soccer; Greeks
  - Photo Negatives, October 1999 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Contents: 12 negative storage pages. Topics: Homecoming; cabaret; T. Deluca; Janick Jodi Rell; History thing; Chinese teacher
  - Photo Negatives, November 1999 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Contents: 8 negative storage pages. Topics: Project Linus; construction; film symposium; student art; women's studies; WCSU football; newman dinner; University Hall
  - Photo Negatives, December 1999 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Contents: 4 negative storage pages. Topics: student totem; blood drive; truman warner archives; student art
  - Photo Negatives, February 2000 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    Contents: 12 negative storage pages. Topics: Inquiring photographer; business page;JLA Lecture; Harlem Globetrotters; Circus/Clubs Day; psychic fair; faculty art show; Meet the Greeks; Random filler; Sigma chi; derby days; house of blue leaves
  - Photo Negatives, March 2000 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    Contents: 6 negative storage pages. Topics: Dorm story; mind reader; newbury hall damages; suburbia open forum; pick-a-major fair; voter registration
  - Photo Negatives, April 2000 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    Contents: 11 negative storage pages. Topics: ECN at O'Neil Center; ADPi Fashion Show; women in politics; inquiring photographer & business page; JobDirect.Com & J-Store; bands; band & choir show; Ricky Corey Recital; Lacrosse; Dan Davis lecture; blood drive; CAREER FAIR; Samantha & Casandra Stevenson
  - Photo Negatives, May 2000 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    Contents: 8 negative storage pages. Topics: Fairfield Hall Luau; Spring Carnival; Inquiring photog.; Dance recital "Colors"; Jane Goodall Lecture (outside); Art Show: Students in White Hall; Serial Killers lecture; Jean Kilbourne Lecture; Violence presentation
  - Photo Negatives, September 2000 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    Contents: 8 negative storage pages. Topics: SGA Executives; Clinton; IQ; Holistic Health Seminar; Irish festival
  - Photo Negatives, October 2000 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Contents: 17 negative storage pages. Topics: Football; Homecoming parade; new professors; Linda Wagner; Jeff Schlicht; Dr. Traore; Dr. Lawrence Immohr; Dr. Edwin Wray; Dr. Russell Hirshfield; Dr. Edward Fox; Dr. Weglarz; Hypnotist; street fair; "Who Gives a ___ Anyway"; Old Main Asbestos; protesting; homecoming; library; Raymond Hoeston; IQ; haunted; childcare; parking
  - Photo Negatives, November 2000 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    Contents: 1 negative storage pages. Topics: New professors; cupee
  - Photo Negatives, December 2000 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    Contents: 2 negative storage pages. Topics: People of Color reception; bridgestone/firestone recall; new professors
  - Photo Negatives, February 2001 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    Contents: 4 negative storage pages. Topics: Vigil Iraq; IQ; Circus protest; snow
  - Instructions for using Photo Morgue, 1995-1998; 8 Sheets (Box 1, Folder 44)